<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on R Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python &amp; R</title>
      <link>/blog/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python/</guid>
      <description>It may seem like Python and R have nothing in common. However, they can sometimes be used interchangeably. While only a short and sweet example is given, it just goes to show that R and Python can exist harmoniously.
#R library(reticulate) #Python import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns iris=sns.load_dataset(&amp;#39;iris&amp;#39;) length=iris[&amp;quot;petal_length&amp;quot;] width=iris[&amp;quot;petal_width&amp;quot;] #R library(dplyr) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;: ## ## filter, lag ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, union L&amp;lt;-py$length L%&amp;gt;%head() ## 0 1 2 3 4 5 ## 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Testing, and Classification</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This dataset, “heart”, was found on kaggle.com. The data was collected in a hospital from 303 willing participants; the goal was to find possible trends in order to predict certain cardiovascular events or find any clear indications of heart health. It originially featured a set of 14 attributes that play a role in heart disease. Some of these variables were removed and some were renamed in order to create a dataset that is readily usable for this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis by Jessica Martin</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the following document, two separate data sets, both of which were found from https://github.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday, will be combined and examined.
The first dataset, named “global_mortality” contains mortality data for 228 political entities (mostly independent countries) for all years between 1990-2016. In this dataset, the mortality rate from 32 distinct factors is recorded as a percentage of the total deaths for each year in each country. In the second dataset, named “lifeexp”, 241 political entities (which I will refer to as countries, for simplicity), are presented along with the life expectancy of each country for years 1950-2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>